<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>DataSmithing</title><link href="https://www.datasmithing.com/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://www.datasmithing.com/feeds/all.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://www.datasmithing.com/</id><updated>2019-08-26T00:00:00-04:00</updated><entry><title>My Imperfect Start</title><link href="https://www.datasmithing.com/first-post.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-08-26T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2019-08-26T00:00:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Melissa Smith</name></author><id>tag:www.datasmithing.com,2019-08-26:/first-post.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;And so it begins...&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Two weeks ago, after meeting with a habit coach client for the first time, I came across this article from James Clear, &lt;a href="https://getpocket.com/explore/item/the-power-of-imperfect-starts"&gt;The Power of Imperfect Starts&lt;/a&gt;. The article has A TON of helpful insights, but the key insight I'm holding onto today is one I've know for ages in terms of habit building: "Start small... There will be plenty of time for optimization later."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So here's to my imperfect start. My logo's not done. My site design is very much not what I'd like. My newsletter sign-ups aren't in flight yet. But all of that is absolutely fine. It's not what I'd prefer. Of course not. But allowing myself an imperfect start means that nothing else can hold me back from starting. This is it. I'm starting. And I can feel the relief that comes with it. Now that I've wrangled my static site generator so I can post, everything else has changed from a road block that's holding me back to something optional I can tweak when I'm ready.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, &lt;code&gt;Hello World&lt;/code&gt;. Someday there will be a comment button where I can invite you to tell me about your imperfect starts. But in the meantime, revel in the imperfections of mine. ;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Contact me at melissa@datasmithing.com so I can help you make your imperfect start. &lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="habits"></category><category term="starts"></category></entry><entry><title>What is a Data Scientist?</title><link href="https://www.datasmithing.com/data-scientist.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-07-01T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2019-07-01T00:00:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Melissa Smith</name></author><id>tag:www.datasmithing.com,2019-07-01:/data-scientist.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Data scientists collaborate with business leaders and domain experts to unravel the mysteries and insights buried within an industry or company’s data. We are curious and ask questions ranging from big-picture questions that clarify goals to detailed questions to guide analysis and understanding. We build visualizations to illustrate patterns …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Data scientists collaborate with business leaders and domain experts to unravel the mysteries and insights buried within an industry or company’s data. We are curious and ask questions ranging from big-picture questions that clarify goals to detailed questions to guide analysis and understanding. We build visualizations to illustrate patterns or anomalies. We use statistics to analyze the impact of changes. We build models to generate predictions based on patterns, and we assess how well those models perform as your data grows and the world around us changes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What secrets does your data hold? What mysteries keep you up at night? How can I help you understand your market and your customers? Contact me at melissa@datasmithing.com to start finding answers.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>Data Science vs. Habit Coaching</title><link href="https://www.datasmithing.com/ds-v-hc.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-07-01T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2019-07-01T00:00:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Melissa Smith</name></author><id>tag:www.datasmithing.com,2019-07-01:/ds-v-hc.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;There’s more overlap between these two roles than you might think. At their heart, they involve asking deep, challenging questions to fully understand the dynamics of whatever problem needs to be solved. In each case, I analyze events or behaviors and use insights from those patterns to increase success …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;There’s more overlap between these two roles than you might think. At their heart, they involve asking deep, challenging questions to fully understand the dynamics of whatever problem needs to be solved. In each case, I analyze events or behaviors and use insights from those patterns to increase success. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Data science uses past and present patterns to predict future behavior. With habit coaching I analyze past patterns and circumstances to understand how we might adapt your environment or strategies to disrupt and radically change your success.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Being involved in both keeps my analysis and problem solving skills sharp. And it keeps those analyses grounded: it’s easy to get buried during analysis, to lose sight of the bigger picture. But habit coaching constantly reminds me that while the analysis is helpful, if it doesn’t help us move towards actionable change, then it’s just navel gazing. &lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="habit coaching"></category><category term="data science"></category></entry><entry><title>What is a Habit Coach?</title><link href="https://www.datasmithing.com/habit-coach.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-07-01T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2019-07-01T00:00:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Melissa Smith</name></author><id>tag:www.datasmithing.com,2019-07-01:/habit-coach.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Questioner, Data Scientist, Habit Coach&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Habits are the building blocks of so many aspects of our lives. They let us autopilot towards goals, happiness, health, and fulfillment. But what happens when you have trouble setting habits? What happens when you have challenging goals that push you far out of your comfort zone and into familiar patterns of overwhelm, distraction, avoidance, or self-defeat? What happens when you have goals you know you NEED to pursup but you don't really WANT to pursue? What happens when you keep getting distracted from your goals by the hustle and bustle of life?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That's where I can help you!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm so much more than an accountability partner or cheerleader. I'll actively list to what's keeping your success out of reach. We'll solve problems around your goals and habits and run weekly experiments to find out what does and doesn't work for your individual needs. We'll start building momentum towards your goals and have a ton of fun along the way. Contact me at melissa@datasmithing.com for more information.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry></feed>