<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>DataSmithing - Letters</title><link href="https://www.datasmithing.com/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://www.datasmithing.com/feeds/letters.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://www.datasmithing.com/</id><updated>2019-08-26T00:00:00-04:00</updated><entry><title>My Imperfect Start</title><link href="https://www.datasmithing.com/first-post.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-08-26T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2019-08-26T00:00:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Melissa Smith</name></author><id>tag:www.datasmithing.com,2019-08-26:/first-post.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;And so it begins...&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Two weeks ago, after meeting with a habit coach client for the first time, I came across this article from James Clear, &lt;a href="https://getpocket.com/explore/item/the-power-of-imperfect-starts"&gt;The Power of Imperfect Starts&lt;/a&gt;. The article has A TON of helpful insights, but the key insight I'm holding onto today is one I've know for ages in terms of habit building: "Start small... There will be plenty of time for optimization later."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So here's to my imperfect start. My logo's not done. My site design is very much not what I'd like. My newsletter sign-ups aren't in flight yet. But all of that is absolutely fine. It's not what I'd prefer. Of course not. But allowing myself an imperfect start means that nothing else can hold me back from starting. This is it. I'm starting. And I can feel the relief that comes with it. Now that I've wrangled my static site generator so I can post, everything else has changed from a road block that's holding me back to something optional I can tweak when I'm ready.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, &lt;code&gt;Hello World&lt;/code&gt;. Someday there will be a comment button where I can invite you to tell me about your imperfect starts. But in the meantime, revel in the imperfections of mine. ;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Contact me at melissa@datasmithing.com so I can help you make your imperfect start. &lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="habits"></category><category term="starts"></category></entry></feed>