<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>DataSmithing - Letters</title><link href="https://www.datasmithing.com/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://www.datasmithing.com/feeds/letters.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://www.datasmithing.com/</id><updated>2019-09-16T00:00:00-04:00</updated><entry><title>Quarterly Goals: Fall 2019</title><link href="https://www.datasmithing.com/Q4-2019-goals.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-09-16T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2019-09-16T00:00:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Melissa Smith</name></author><id>tag:www.datasmithing.com,2019-09-16:/Q4-2019-goals.html</id><summary type="html"></summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;A strategy that's helped me prioritize and limit where I want to change and grow is developing and tracking quarterly goals. Three months is an optimal time frame for goals; it's enough time to visualize your long-term path, but it's not so long term that you can't imagine what the finish line looks like. This quarter I'll be writing about my own goals and habits each week to demonstrate the kind of back and forth I have with my clients when I have sessions with them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This quarter I really want to tackle a problem that's been nagging me since I made the switch back to freelancing and working from home. This time around, I've had trouble finding my rhythm, and I've found myself spinning my wheels more than I did when I first worked from home. So my overarching goal is to re-structure life so that it suits the freedom of the freelancing lifestyle while dodging my Achilles heel: situations where I try to optimize zero-constraint problems (more on that next month). This big goal breaks down into three areas: Schedule, Sleep, and Health. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At first glance, health might look like an oddball. But working from home offers so many possibilities for incorporating a healthy, activite lifestyle into my day. But it equally offers the ability to develop a divit in your couch from sitting cross-legged with your laptop and a pile of cats. Ask me how I know!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These three areas probably mean something different to everyone, so here's a peak into what they mean to me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Schedule: I live in the paradox of needing the structure and rhythm that a schedule provides, but rebelling (that's right... against myself) if the schedule feels too arbitrary. So I want to build a schedule that instills enough structure to keep me grounded and honoring my priorities while maintaining flexibility and freedom. Based on my experiences in this past quarter, rather than try to Schedule All The Things up front, I need to start small, build a little each week, and tweak.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sleep: I’ve been struggling with some insomnia lately. Along with the obvious health issues, frustration, and exhaustion, I lose a lot of enjoyable and possibly productive hours from the day just in trying to go to sleep. When morning rolls around, it's super easy to turn the alarm off and go back to sleep, which throws off my whole day and sets me up for another night of not being able to fall asleep. And without a relatively set sleep schedule, how can I possibly schedule anything else?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Health: I need to shed a few pounds by moving more throughout the day, maintaining my gym habit, and tidying up my diet. Plus, I just generally miss feeling strong and fit. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So that's it. Those are my goals! See you in three months!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ha!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are two absolutely critical next steps to making these goals successful. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, I've got to define what success for each goal looks like. And with goals as broad as these, I'll probably end up breaking them down into a few smaller, measurable goals. I'll spend some time thinking through questions like, "What's does the 'ideal' schedule accomplish for me?", "How do I know that I've kicked the insomnia problem?", and "What does a healthy Melissa look like? What can that Melissa do that current Melissa can't?" These aren't just theoretical questions; being able to measure these goals is how I'll know whether or not I'm on track. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Secondly, I'll need to break each of the measureable goals down into habits. Habits are the engine that will move me along the path to success. It will take some experimentation and trying out different strategies. Each habit will get measured and tracked in some fashion. And most importantly, each habit gets compared to the goals. The habits aren't busy work. Even if a habit is easy to adopt, if it doesn't seem to end up helping me towards the goal, it should get swapped with something more effective. For example, let's say I set my workout clothes out every night to give me a visual reminder to go to the gym. If that habit doesn't actually result in more gym visits, then I should stop and try something else. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next Monday, I'll write out how I make the schedule, sleep, and health goals measurable. The week after, I'll begin working on the execution level, and after that, I'll check-in every week on how well that week's habits worked and what tweaks I'll make for the next week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Does this approach appeal to you? How do you tackle goals? Contact me at melissa@datasmithing.com if I can help!&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Habits"></category><category term="Goals"></category><category term="Fall 2019"></category></entry><entry><title>My Imperfect Start</title><link href="https://www.datasmithing.com/first-post.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-08-26T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2019-08-26T00:00:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Melissa Smith</name></author><id>tag:www.datasmithing.com,2019-08-26:/first-post.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;And so it begins...&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Two weeks ago, after meeting with a habit coach client for the first time, I came across this article from James Clear, &lt;a href="https://getpocket.com/explore/item/the-power-of-imperfect-starts"&gt;The Power of Imperfect Starts&lt;/a&gt;. The article has A TON of helpful insights, but the key insight I'm holding onto today is one I've know for ages in terms of habit building: "Start small... There will be plenty of time for optimization later."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So here's to my imperfect start. My logo's not done. My site design is very much not what I'd like. My newsletter sign-ups aren't in flight yet. But all of that is absolutely fine. It's not what I'd prefer. Of course not. But allowing myself an imperfect start means that nothing else can hold me back from starting. This is it. I'm starting. And I can feel the relief that comes with it. Now that I've wrangled my static site generator so I can post, everything else has changed from a road block that's holding me back to something optional I can tweak when I'm ready.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, &lt;code&gt;Hello World&lt;/code&gt;. Someday there will be a comment button where I can invite you to tell me about your imperfect starts. But in the meantime, revel in the imperfections of mine. ;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Contact me at melissa@datasmithing.com so I can help you make your imperfect start. &lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="habits"></category><category term="starts"></category></entry></feed>