<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>DataSmithing - Posts</title><link href="https://www.datasmithing.com/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://www.datasmithing.com/feeds/posts.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://www.datasmithing.com/</id><updated>2020-01-10T00:00:00-05:00</updated><entry><title>My Resolutions for 2020</title><link href="https://www.datasmithing.com/first-half-goals.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-01-10T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-01-10T00:00:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Melissa Smith</name></author><id>tag:www.datasmithing.com,2020-01-10:/first-half-goals.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I love New Year's Resolutions. The idea of a fresh start, hitting the reset button is so liberating to me. But I've always struggled with them. Not that I haven't achieved great things in a year, or had the accountability to stick through working on my resolutions for the whole …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I love New Year's Resolutions. The idea of a fresh start, hitting the reset button is so liberating to me. But I've always struggled with them. Not that I haven't achieved great things in a year, or had the accountability to stick through working on my resolutions for the whole year. But I have definitely had a couple that I have lugged across an entire decade with debatable success.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve decided to shake things up in 2020 and become hyper-focused on finally, at long last, tackling those resolutions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here’s some specific strategies I’ve applied to help make this year’s version of ‘lose weight’ be more successful:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ditch the phrase ‘lose weight’ from my resolution.&lt;/strong&gt; I can’t truly control whether or not I lose weight. What I &lt;em&gt;can&lt;/em&gt; control is the habits I pursue that will very likely lead to weight loss. And ultimately, it’s not just weight loss I want but overall health and strength.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Include specific dates on my habits, where appropriate.&lt;/strong&gt; That gives me some deadlines and ways to achieve milestones of success along the way -- entirely within my control.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Don’t try to do everything at once.&lt;/strong&gt; This applies in two ways. First off, the deadlines give me a way to settle into all of the changes I want to make and slowly get to where I need to be. Slow, achievable changes are more successful. Secondly, for the very first time, I’ve actually limited my resolutions to single focus. I used to have a million each year, and they were ALL OVER the place. Not this year. I might DO the other things, but I’m not committing to doing them until I’ve tackled the first one.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Make it fun.&lt;/strong&gt; I’ve had some fun with how everything is worded. I’m launching many professional and personal projects this year, so I decided to make ‘launch’ a theme for this year. I grin every time I read my list.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So here goes, here’s my official set of resolutions for the first half of 2020.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On June 30th, complete 10 pull-ups using bicep, tricep, and core strength following a lift-off using quadricep muscles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Decrease maximum payload for launch event:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Track nutrient consumption daily using MyFitnessPal or similar tracking system&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Continue gym visits, increasing from 3x weekly to 6x weekly by the end of March.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reintroduce intermittent fasting, experimenting with 10, 12, and 16-hour fasts to determine which best suits my body and lifestyle.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Give up refined sugar in January. Reintroduce in February, limited to 4x per month. Track using treat budget in Beeminder. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Weigh every morning after tooth brushing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Increase horizontal speed to achieve 3 miles in 30 minutes:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Create running and strength training schedule by January 15th to increase duration of running portion of weekly runs and gradually increase speed at achievable pace. I’m currently running 3 miles total at pace of 5.2 mph with a 0.1 mile walk break every 0.5 miles.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Improve chassis flexibility, balance, and durability:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Implement the tiny habit changes in my &lt;a href="https://www.datasmithing.com/category/move-more-2020-anti-challenge.html"&gt;Move More 2020 Anti-Challenge&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Increase maximum distance covered through rotational force:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Starting on February 1, ride exercise bike a minimum of one mile per day during morning wake-up game playing. Identify additional pairing events for biking. Track distance achieved per day. Beat maximum distance achieved 30 times.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ride my non-stationary bike outdoors at least once.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Simulate launch maneuvers:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Every Friday/Saturday gym session (depending on timing of trainer session), execute 50 squats, 5 minutes of planks, and 50 reps on compensated pull-up machine.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Evaluate launch readiness on June 1st and consider additional initiatives for remainder of 2020.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry></feed>